Barbara Hernandez

Full Stack Software Engineer with over ten years professional experience. Well versed in front-end development including the modern and legacy front-end frameworks. Comfortable creating efficient back-end applications whether they interface with external APIs or relational or non-relational databases. A team player who steps up to any challenge and brings everyone to the next level together.

SKILLS

React, React Native, Angular, Typescript, JavaScript, jQuery, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Bootstrap, Jest, Go, Java, Spring, Spring Boot, AWS, Google Cloud(GCP), Jenkins, GIT (Source Control), Node.js, REST, API, Express, SQL, MySQL, Firebase, MongoDB, and WordPress.

EXPERIENCE

Atrium Staffing — Senior Software Engineer — Cox Communications

Atlanta, GA | SEPTEMBER 2021 - MARCH 2024

- Contributed to demo and pilot software for the front-end using Angular and typescript and back-end using Go for a logistics start up venture which won contracts in healthcare and manufacturing worth over 2.5 million dollars.
- Conceptualized and guided into production dozens of new features for both front-end and back-end based on client feedback in a collaborative, iterative environment.
- Led Quality Assurance efforts, including managing contractors both domestic and near shore.
- Oversaw the migration of data from Firestore to BigQuery datasets, ensuring no loss or corruption of data.
- Implemented a suite of automated tests using Cypress for two applications, which increased the speed of QA processes by over 20%.
- Collaborated with DevOps to create a full CI/CD pipeline complete with automated testing.
- Coached engineering team in adoption of Agile methodology, including a high standard of ticket writing, accurate sprint planning, and open communication via sprint ceremonies.
- Acted as hiring manager for 6 new contractor roles including front-end and back-end developers, QA Engineer, and Data Analyst.

Atos Syntel — *Software Engineer*— Home Depot

Atlanta, GA | OCTOBER 2020 - SEPTEMBER 2021

- Quickly assimilated to and began developing alongside the existing engineering team to create a reusable component library utilizing
 React and Material UI.
- Maintained a high standard of unit test and integration test coverage of the component library for new and existing code.
- Supported micro front-end architecture by working with implementation teams as a front-end expert.
- Created documentation using React and Storybook to facilitate consistent front-end architecture.
- Developed a close working relationship with UX, including joining design meetings, to ensure alignment for new and developing features.
- Produced a set of components which alleviate the burden on implementing teams, while allowing each team to meet business needs.
- Helped identify process improvements, leading to more structured sprints with clearer story point targets.

Cognizant — *Software Engineer* — Macy's

Atlanta, GA | NOVEMBER 2019 - AUGUST 2020

- Developed and maintained highly visible pages for an e-commerce web application for a fortune 500 company with more than 55 million unique monthly visitors, utilizing HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, AMP, and RESTful web services.
- Coordinated Agile workflow with local team and 3 additional teams in New York, San Francisco, and India.
- Led a team of 5 developers to create a React Native POC with Firebase database demonstrating new features for mobile applications.
- Contributed to Java based POC projects with microservice architecture using Spring/Spring Boot, deployed with Jenkins and AWS.
- Managed Source Control using GIT, supporting less experienced team members.
- Created documentation for new hires which reduced set-up time of the local environment from roughly one week to a single day.
- Participated with colleagues in the IBM Covid-19 Hackathon to create a MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node) application to show COVID-19 data by state with data pulled from an open source API, including IBM Watson chat client to provide further information and additional customization and social media feeds.

Home Care Institute — *Software and Development Manager*

Johns Creek, GA | SEPTEMBER 2013 - MAY 2019

- Coordinated upgrades and maintenance of web applications with React based front-end and Java back-end e-learning application with over 25,000 active users.
- Developed and Maintained all public-facing web applications using WordPress, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Built a React/Node. Js time tracking application using Bootstrap and a SQL database, saving hundreds of dollars per employee per year.
- Implemented SCSS to streamline per-client customization of web applications.
- Trained over 100 clients to use beginner and advanced features of both web application and mobile application.
- Created and Maintained documentation for internal and client usage.

JET Programme — Assistant Language Teacher

Kamikitayama-mura, Japan | AUGUST 2012 - AUGUST 2013

EDUCATION

University of Georgia — A.B. Linguistics, A.B. Spanish Language & Literature

Graduated May 2012 Magna Cum Laude

Minor in Japanese Studies

Georgia Institute of Technology Professional Education — *Certificate of Full Stack Web Development*

This 6 month MERN stack focused program covered technical skills, best practices, taking a project from idea through design into production, and using version control to facilitate team work.

Georgia Institute of Technology Professional Education — Certificate of Accelerated Java Boot Camp

This highly selective accelerated boot camp accepted the 25 top candidates, with only 16 eventually offered a position by the sponsor after graduation. Curriculum was designed to give developers sufficient knowledge of Java to work on client projects in just 12 weeks of full time study.